hi spring fans in this installment
嗨，本期春季粉丝
spring tips we're gonna look at the
春天的技巧，我们要看看
spring state machine now spring state
Spring Statemachine现在Spring 状态
machine is a project allows us to
机器是一个项目，使我们能够
describe just that state machines
只描述状态机
basically things that contain well known
基本上包含众所周知的东西
well understood transitions from one
从一个很好理解的过渡
state to another
向另一个国家陈述
you have probably built a million state
你可能已经建立了一百万个州
machines in your life if you've ever
生活中的机器
done any kind of programming at all any
完全可以进行任何类型的编程
kind of if-then-else statement for
的if-then-else语句
example at some point will constitute a
这个例子在某个时候会构成一个
state machine a case statement
状态机案例说明
constitutes a state machine anything
构成任何状态机
where you have or deletes or transitions
您拥有或删除或转换的地方
predictable deterministic transitions
可预测的确定性转变
from one state to another and then have
从一种状态到另一种状态
action associated with that that's a
与之相关的动作是
state machine so a state machine is a
状态机，所以状态机是
very fundamental part of what we do but
我们所做的非常基本的部分
as often as not it boils down into these
往往不归结为这些
ugly sort of if statements are elf
丑陋的if语句是小精灵
statements and things like that and
陈述之类的东西，以及
worse if you have complex state then you
更糟糕的是，如果您有复杂的状态，那么您
have to evaluate that state at the site
必须在现场评估该状态
where you're keeping this weight where
你在哪里保持这个体重
you're actually processing the state as
您实际上正在将状态处理为
opposed to at a higher level so it
反对更高层次的
becomes very useful to extricate this
使解脱变得非常有用
the the flow of the progressions of of
的进展流
the business object from one state to
从一个状态到
another into a separate plane a separate
另一个进入一个单独的平面
place where you can model it we can we
我们可以在这里建模的地方
can reason about it and then have the
可以对此进行推理，然后
code the actual business logic that's
编码实际的业务逻辑
associated with that respond to those
与那些相关的回应
state changes right so you've got
状态更改正确，所以您有
instead of a bunch of business logic
而不是一堆业务逻辑
where you have a whole bunch of
你有一堆
if-then-else statements at the site
该站点上的if-then-else语句
where you're making the decision
您在哪里做决定
deciding what to do next instead of
决定下一步做什么而不是
having that you keep this business logic
保持您的业务逻辑
in a single place and then have actions
在一个地方然后采取行动
or handlers or whatever or you know some
或经理或其他人，或者您知道一些
way of describing what should happen
描述应该发生什么的方式
based in that state this is a it's it's
基于该状态，这是它的
it's useful because if you want to
这很有用，因为如果您想
change the workflow front to change the
更改工作流前端以更改
progression of one thing to another you
一件事发展到另一件事
can do so in a single place as opposed
可以在一个地方做到这一点
to having to scour all the different
不得不冲刷所有不同的东西
layers in the codebase where you have
您拥有的代码库中的图层
all these complex decisions so state
所有这些复杂的决定都这样说
machines are valuable and for that
机器很有价值，为此
reason they also form they also give us
他们也形成的原因也给了我们
a nice way to think about the
一种思考问题的好方法
progressions of our application how
我们的应用进展如何
things should happen how they should
事情应该发生怎么办
move modeling your business project in
在其中进行业务项目建模
terms of the state machine is a very
状态机的条件是非常
useful idea even if you don't plan on
有用的想法，即使你不打算
using at the code level a state machine
在代码级别使用状态机
and this is for example why UML has
例如，这就是为什么UML具有
support for describing state machines
支持描述状态机
write state machines are very very
写状态机非常非常
important part of what we
我们重要的部分
doing at some point people want to
人们想在某个时候做
connect a business with the code and the
将业务与代码和
state machine provides a a logical place
状态机提供了一个合理的地方
where both business and technology
商业和技术都在这里
people can sort of interface right the
人们可以对界面进行排序
the business heuristics of what it makes
商业启发法
sense for our business as a as an
对我们的业务而言
organization can be modeled in terms of
组织可以按照以下方式建模
state machine and then that can be
状态机，然后可以是
translated into code state machines give
翻译成代码状态机给
us a way to describe state as well over
我们也是一种描述状态的方式
long-running process right so if you
长期运行的过程，所以如果您
have a long-running process with lots of
具有长期运行的过程
moving parts it can be very useful to be
运动部件，这可能非常有用
able to look at something and say oh
能够看一些东西然后说哦
where are we in this progress right in
我们在哪里取得进展
this process so if any particular one
这个过程，如果有的话
step in the process should fail we can
该过程中的步骤应该失败，我们可以
we can look at the at the the state
我们可以看看状态
machine to say okay we should resume
机器说好，我们应该恢复
from here right that we run step two of
从这里开始，我们执行
five state machines to have the benefit
五种状态机受益
of being queryable you can interrogate
可以查询
them you can ask them where are we you
他们可以问他们我们在哪里
know in this fulfillment flow for
在此履行流程中知道
example suppose I'm fulfilling an order
例子假设我正在执行订单
or something like that and we have a
或类似的东西，我们有一个
number of steps involved in doing that
这样做涉及的步骤数
from both people and Anton Mis actors
来自人和安东·米斯（Anton Mis）演员
being able to poke at the the state
可以戳国家
machine and go okay we're we're on step
机器，走吧，我们在前进
two what happens next okay this is step
两个接下来会发生什么，好的，这是步骤
three and so on it's very very useful so
三个等等非常有用，所以
state machine to give us a lot of
状态机给我们很多
benefits they're convenient as a way of
好处是它们很方便
interchanging ideas between technology
技术之间的观念互换
and business they're convenient because
和商务上他们很方便，因为
they give us a way to keep track of the
他们给我们提供了一种方式来跟踪
progression of some sort of work
某种工作的进展
especially useful in a distributed
在分布式环境中特别有用
system scenario we have potentially a
系统场景中，我们有可能
lot of moving parts a lot of actors in a
很多动作部分，很多演员
system and you want to be able to
系统，您希望能够
understand and track their progression
了解并跟踪其进度
their or their activity so state
他们或他们的活动如此陈述
machines are fundamentally a very simple
机器从根本上讲非常简单
thing if you take this idea step further
如果您将这个想法更进一步的话
if you have this idea that you want to
如果您有这个想法想要
extricate the the state or the the
摆脱国家或
movement of from one state to another to
从一个国家到另一个国家的运动
a you know higher order construct you
你知道高阶构造你
see a lot of different options out there
看到很多不同的选择
and a lot of them tend to be very fairly
他们中的很多人往往非常公平
heavy workflow engine so process you
繁重的工作流引擎，为您处理
know business process management
了解业务流程管理
solutions and
解决方案和
I think that would be a good subject for
我认为这将是一个很好的主题
another installment certainly right I
我肯定是另一期
I've done talks and articles and so on
我已经做过讲座和文章等等
on for example activity and spring right
例如活动和春季
activity is a BPM in workflow engine
活动是工作流引擎中的BPM
that you can use with spring boot and
可以与Spring Boot一起使用
these days actually activity has a few
这些天实际上活动有一些
Forks so come on commune de has a fork
叉子，所以在公社上有叉子
of it a new company called global it's
其中有一家名为global的新公司
based on activity as well so there's a
基于活动，所以有一个
lot of interesting sort of fertile
很多有趣的肥沃的
research just being done in that one
研究只是在那一个
particular corner of the of the bpmn
bpmn的特定角
universe and not to mention all the
宇宙，更不用说所有
other implementations out there so
其他实现方式
there's certainly a lot there we could
当然有很多我们可以
talk about in other installments but
在其他部分谈论
today I want to focus on a much lighter
今天我想集中精力
weight project called spring state
重量项目称为Spring 状态
machine which gives you a very simple
机器，它给你非常简单
DSL for describing state machines that's
DSL，用于描述状态机
it it's in and you can you can do things
它在里面，你可以做些事情
like persist the state of the state
像坚持状态一样
machine if you want you can describe
机器，如果你想你可以描述
complex hierarchical progressions and
复杂的等级进展和
you know transitions if you want but all
你知道过渡，如果你想，但所有
these things you have to add extra right
这些东西你必须增加额外的权利
they by default is just a DSL for
默认情况下，它们只是一个DSL
describing states and their and their
描述状态及其状态
progressions and what events can
进展以及哪些事件可以
couldn't activate those transitions so
无法激活这些过渡，因此
we're going to go ahead and build a
我们将继续建立一个
brand new project here today and at the
今天和这里的全新项目
normal place here so I wanted to see
正常的地方在这里，所以我想看看
okay start stringing i/o will build an
好吧，开始穿线I / O会建立一个
application I'm gonna call this order
我要叫这个应用程序
service alright and when we don't need
服务很好，当我们不需要时
anything here except for perhaps the web
除了网路以外，这里的一切
support so let's go ahead and well I
支持，让我们继续前进，好吧，我
mean I'm not sure if we need that do we
意思是我不确定我们是否需要
yeah we don't need it
是的，我们不需要它
let's leave off so we'll build an
让我们离开，所以我们将建立一个
application here and hit generate you
在这里申请并点击产生您
know I do want some stuff I want JDBC I
知道我确实想要一些我想要JDBC的东西
want JP rather I don't want h2 so let me
我想要JP，而不想要h2，所以让我
kill the errantly downloaded version
杀死错误下载的版本
there okay so what JDBC JPA
那里好，那么JDBC JPA是什么
and I think that'll do I think that's on
我认为那会继续
Lombok certainly okay very good so now
龙目岛当然很好，所以现在
notice that right now there is no
注意，现在没有
checkbox and I think that will change
复选框，我认为这将会改变
pretty soon well if not all I'll
很快，如果不是全部的话
certainly add
当然添加
but in the meantime we'll just have to
但与此同时，我们只需要
add it ourselves it's just a one little
自己添加它只是一个小
dependency it's not a very large
依赖性不是很大
divinity there's not a it's not a whole
神性不是一个整体
ecosystem of projects it's just one
项目生态系统只是其中之一
library one project rather who and small
图书馆一个项目，而不是谁和小
project with that a few interesting
有一些有趣的项目
modules you can use it if you want any
您可以使用任何模块
or don't write I happen to like it I
还是不写我碰巧喜欢我
hope I think it fits a very nice you
希望我觉得很适合你
know space there's a there's a really a
知道空间有一个真的
nice space for describing complex
描述复杂的好空间
transitions and for for reconciling
过渡和调和
those transitions if you've ever used
这些过渡（如果您曾经使用过）
the saga pattern right this is the saga
传奇模式对，这就是传奇
pattern requires you to have a saga
模式要求你有一个传奇
execution coordinator and you can model
执行协调员，您可以建模
that with spring state machine for
用Spring Statemachine
example the saga saga pattern is a great
例子saga saga模式很棒
way of building of achieving consensus
建立共识的方式
across multiple you know work workloads
跨多个您知道的工作负载
across multiple units of work and a
跨多个工作单元
distributed system or released in in a
分布式系统或发布在
long-running single node transaction so
长期运行的单节点事务
that's a good example right you could
这是一个很好的例子，你可以
use the spring state machine to achieve
用Spring Statemachine来实现
that you can model more complex business
您可以为更复杂的业务建模
processes that need some sort of
需要某种形式的过程
representation separate from the actual
代表与实际分开
implementation you could do that with
实现，您可以使用
spring state machine as well okay so
Spring Statemachine也可以
let's suppose we have a very simple
假设我们有一个非常简单的
order service okay so we're gonna first
订购服务还可以，所以我们先
add our dependency here now I have the
现在在这里添加我们的依赖项
font a little too small there let me
字体有点太小了，让我
make the font just a little larger
使字体变大一点
all right 22 good and we're gonna go
好的22好，我们要去了
ahead and add spring state machine I
提前添加Spring StatemachineI
have for my own purposes here kept the
为了我自己的目的在这里保留了
dependency off to the side I won't add
我不会添加的依赖
that in here alright one two three one
在这里一二三一
two three it's spring state machine
二三是Spring Statemachine
that's one that's a version we're gonna
那是我们要去的版本
use and so we can create a new service
使用，因此我们可以创建新服务
now before we do that let's actually
现在在我们这样做之前
configure the the state machine itself
配置状态机本身
so the first thing we need is to to
所以我们要做的第一件事是
create configuration class we're going
创建我们要去的配置类
to say class a simple enum state machine
说一个简单的枚举状态机
configuration extends state machine
配置扩展状态机
configure adapter right and what we're
配置适配器的权利以及我们
gonna do is we're going to model a state
我们要做的是为国家建模
machine that has well-known states that
具有众所周知状态的机器
we spawn two well-known events and this
我们产生了两个众所周知的事件
is gonna be a common thing you'll see
会成为平常的事情
this a lot and so the states you needed
这很多，所以你需要的状态
you know you can do it you can describe
你知道你可以做到，你可以描述
those states in terms of those strings
根据那些字符串的状态
or you can describe them in terms of you
或者你可以用你自己来形容
know which i think is actually a much
知道我认为这实际上是很多
more sort of a palatable option here
这里有更多可口的选择
because it gives you a nice type safe
因为它给你一个很好的类型安全
way of describing well-known states so
这样描述已知状态的方式
enum order states and we're gonna say
枚举顺序状态，我们要说
that there's a when when somebody makes
有人做某事的时候
an order on some sort of a taylor
某种泰勒上的命令
website they'll have a an order they get
网站上将收到他们的订单
submitted so I'm gonna say submitted and
提交，所以我要说提交和
paid and what else fulfilled I guess
有偿，还有什么我想
that's when somebody you know takes the
那就是你认识的人拿走
order put it in a box labels it stamps
订单放进盒子，盖上邮票
it sends it out or cancelled right so
它发出它或取消它，所以
whatever reason you might cancel the
无论出于何种原因，您都可以取消
order and we could have more complex
订单，我们可能会更复杂
business hogr care around when
何时进行商业笑护
somebody's allowed to cancel it but
有人可以取消它，但是
let's just say for now that you can
现在就说您可以
cancel it at any time and then there are
随时取消它，然后有
events well-known events that trigger
事件触发的知名事件
these state changes so for example when
这些状态会发生变化，例如
somebody sends the pay event then it
有人发送付款事件，然后
goes to the paid state right so once
正确地进入有偿状态
that when somebody sends the fulfill
当有人发送履行
event it goes to the fulfilled state and
事件进入完成状态
of course when somebody sends the cancel
当然，当有人发送取消消息时
event it goes to the canceled state so
事件进入取消状态，因此
now what that's done we're gonna say
现在我们要做的是说
that we're gonna build a state machine
我们要建立一个状态机
with these order states
这些订单状态
all right it's a states are first and
好吧，这是一个国家，首先
then events are a second so orbit events
那么事件是第二个轨道事件
alright now this is a configuration
好了，这是一个配置
class and we want to use the at enable
类，我们想使用at enable
state machine factory right this is the
状态机工厂对，这是
this this refers to the ability of
这是指能力
spring state machine to either keep one
Spring Statemachine要么保留一个
sort of global state machine or two to
一种或两种全局状态机
vend new instances of the state machine
出售状态机的新实例
for whatever your purposes and I want to
出于您的目的，我想
actually been different instances so I'm
实际上是不同的情况，所以我
gonna use the factory mechanism here now
现在要在这里使用工厂机制
it's my understanding that the system
据我了解，该系统
there is actually you could use the
实际上，您可以使用
spring state machine project without
没有状态的Spring State Machine项目
spring right the I'm using a little
春天吧，我正在用一点
spring cuz I think it it fits there but
春天，因为我认为它适合那里，但是
it is such a simple library
它是如此简单
fundamentally and there is just a
从根本上来说，只有一个
builder DSL that you can use but I think
您可以使用的构建器DSL，但我认为
it's fine to use it as is with this so
可以按原样使用它，所以
first thing we have to do we actually
我们要做的第一件事实际上
have two things that we need to do three
我们要做两件事
things rather first we need to configure
首先，我们需要配置
the engine itself right and so will
引擎本身正确，因此
override the configure let's see state
覆盖配置让我们看看状态
machine configuration configure is the
机器配置configure是
engine itself and here we're gonna say
引擎本身，在这里我们要说
config dot I want to change the
配置点我想改变
configuration we're going to start it up
配置，我们将启动它
automatically set that to false and then
自动将其设置为false，然后
we want to specify a listener and
我们要指定一个监听器，
actually we could we don't need this
实际上我们可以不需要
right now but we could provide a state
现在，但我们可以提供一个状态
machine listener right and so here we'd
机器监听器正确，所以在这里
have something that we can use so it's a
有一些我们可以使用的东西
state machine in listener and let's see
侦听器中的状态机，让我们看看
it's a order states order events and we
这是一个订单状态订单事件，我们
override any one of these interface
覆盖这些接口中的任何一个
methods right so I've got a I've got the
方法正确，所以我有一个
adapter here but if I were to override
适配器在这里，但如果我要覆盖
the interface proper I'd get a number of
正确的界面我会得到一些
different callback methods one that's
不同的回调方法是
kind of interesting from you know I
有点有趣，你知道我
think is the the state changed method so
认为是国家改变方法，所以
state changed or entered or exited right
状态已更改，已进入或已退出
and so this allows us to them to see
因此，这使我们能够看到他们
when the state went when the consistent
当状态去的时候一致
machine has gone from one state to
机器已经从一种状态变为
another so let's actually extract that
另一个，让我们实际提取
out into a separate class there and we
在那里进入一个单独的班级，我们
can actually store that right we don't
实际上可以存储我们不拥有的权利
have to keep this actually it's fine we
必须保持这个实际上我们很好
can yeah there we go so there we go
可以呀，我们走了，所以走了
that's my there's my simple adapter
那是我的，我的适配器很简单
these are no application no operation
这些都是没有应用程序就没有操作
based interface method so you can do
基于接口的方法，因此您可以
whatever you want in there all I'm gonna
无论你想要什么，我都会
do is I'm gonna log it and I've got
我要做的是记录下来，我已经
Lombok on the class path so I'm gonna
龙目岛在上课之路，所以我要
use at log to generate a logger and I'll
在日志中使用以生成记录器，我将
just log I'll say log info state changed
只是登录我会说日志信息状态已更改
and the from will be something and we'll
而来自将是某种东西，我们将
talk about that in a second and then two
一会儿再说两个
will be something else and then this so
会是其他的东西，然后这样
let's see string dot format and I'm
让我们看看字符串点格式，我
gonna say from dot to string or actually
要说点到字符串或实际上
let's do from plus okay and then to plus
让我们从加好开始，然后再到加
all right so there's our simple listener
好吧，有一个简单的监听器
this is actually pretty you know you
这其实很漂亮，你知道你
we don't need to do this first but it's
我们不需要先这样做，但是
always nice to I like to have it since
一直很高兴我喜欢
we're using the factory we don't want to
我们正在使用我们不想的工厂
start up a state machine you know a
启动一个你知道的状态机
global one when we start the application
启动应用程序时是全局的
so well we'll disable that immediately
好吧，我们将立即禁用它
first thing now the next thing we want
现在第一件事我们想要的下一件事
to override is the the state machines
要覆盖的是状态机
the state machine states themselves
状态机陈述自己
right so we need to actually tell the
对，所以我们需要实际告诉
state machine about the different states
关于不同状态的状态机
and we use the state machine state
我们使用状态机状态
configure and we'll say states dot with
配置，我们会说点与
States dot initial so what we're going
最初的国家点，所以我们要去
to do is we're going to provide a a a a
要做的是我们将提供aaaa
directed graph we're trying to describe
我们试图描述的有向图
what states can come you know which
你会知道哪些状态
states are the sort of genesis of a
状态是一种起源
state machine which ones are the
状态机是
termination and which ones are
终止，哪些是终止
progressions right which ones are actual
正确的进展
states that can be kept or maintained or
可以保持或维持的状态
whatever so and we can do complex things
无论如何，我们可以做复杂的事情
here we can do a splitting and joining
在这里我们可以进行拆分和合并
and you know we can describe custom
而且您知道我们可以描述自定义
things here but for our purposes we just
事情在这里，但出于我们的目的，我们只是
want to describe which one is the
想描述哪个是
initial one
最初的
so the initial is going to be a
所以最初将是
submitted right so order must order
提交权利，因此必须订购
machines or order states rather submit
机器或订单状态而不是提交
it that's that's the first state that
那就是那第一个状态
our state machine will be in when it
我们的状态机将在
starts up we're gonna have another state
启动，我们将有另一个状态
called
叫
order order States paid and then there
订购订单各国已付款然后有
are two terminal ones and one is called
是两个终端，一个叫做
order States fulfilled and another one
命令各国履行了义务
is called order states dot cancelled all
被称为订单状态点已全部取消
right so there's two two different
对，所以有两个两个不同
states that can finish the finish the
可以完成的状态
workflow so we can either end correctly
工作流程，这样我们就可以正确结束
and unfulfilled or we can cancel right
尚未履行，或者我们可以取消权利
these are both terminal conditions that
这些都是最终条件
workflow the state machine is done if we
如果我们完成状态机的工作流程
enter either of those states all right
可以进入任何一个州
now finally we need to actually describe
现在最后我们需要实际描述
the the transitions from one state to
从一种状态到
another so here
另一个在这里
we'll use the state machine transition
我们将使用状态机转换
configure right so let's see that is
正确配置，让我们看看这是
this one here and here
这个这里和这里
when I say transition it's dots and here
当我说过渡时，这里是点
you can see there's a lot of different
你会看到有很多不同
types
类型
of transitions right a lot of different
过渡的权利有很多不同
ways to to a lot of different ways for
有很多不同的方式
transitions to be triggered or activated
要触发或激活的转换
and a lot of different kinds of
还有很多不同种类的
[Music]
[音乐]
transitions themselves and things that
过渡自己和事物
you can actually do with them so if you
你实际上可以和他们在一起，所以如果你
for example had a state machine that
例如有一个状态机
just start it went from start to you
刚开始，它从头开始
know a to a to z right if you had from a
如果你从a知道a到a到z
and then B and then C and then D
然后是B然后是C然后是D
directly with absolutely no intervention
直接进行，完全无需干预
at all that'd be called a local
完全被称为本地
transition right you could say with
您可以说的过渡权
local source and the source would be
本地来源，来源将是
let's say for example order states dot
例如说订单状态点
submitted dot and then the target would
提交点，然后目标
be order states what are we safe
被命令说我们安全吗
fulfilled yeah fulfilled so that would
是的，是的，所以会
be if we're to create a state machine
如果我们要创建一个状态机
like that it would start up it would go
这样它会启动它会
from submitted directly to fulfilled and
从直接提交到实现，以及
that will just be automatic as soon as
只要尽快
the program started it would continue
该程序启动它将继续
doing that which isn't that useful
这样做没什么用
usually you want to you know unless you
通常你想知道，除非你
want to automatically advance the token
想要自动推进令牌
you know represented or their token
你知道代表或他们的令牌
representing each state you want to
代表您想要的每个州
automatically advance it to the next
自动将其前进到下一个
state when the application starts up or
说明应用程序何时启动或
what based on it having entered some
基于它进入了什么
other state then this is probably useful
其他状态则可能有用
but in our case we can you know we want
但就我们而言，我们可以知道
our state machine to change only in
我们的状态机只在
response to some sort of event so far
到目前为止对某种事件的反应
more commonly I find that I use with
更常见的是，我发现
external so with external gives you
外在的，所以外在给你
three options here in the DSL so you
DSL中的三个选项让您
specify the source so one source is
指定来源，因此一个来源是
submitted right and the target is going
提交权利，目标正在
to be paid right and then the event that
得到报酬，然后
can trigger that transition is the pay
可以触发过渡就是报酬
event all right so that's one you know
好吧，那是你所知道的
state transition that we care about
我们关心的状态转换
another one is and here we're gonna say
另一个是，在这里我们要说
source or dot with external first dot
源或带有外部第一个点的点
let's see keep this little cleaner let's
让我们来看看保持这个小清洁剂吧
try it like that there we go so source
像那样尝试吧，我们去了这么多源
paid target is fulfilled
已达成付费目标
and event is fulfill all right there we
事件在那里实现，我们
go that's you know the another
去那你就知道另一个
progression so it'll it'll go from
进展，所以它会从
submitted to paid with the pavement and
随行并付清
then from there to go from paid to
然后从那里到付费
fulfilled with the fulfill event what
满足事件的完成
else to want with external I'm sorry and
其他要与外部对不起
with external source order states
具有外部源订单状态
submitted to cancel so one of able to
提交取消，因此能够
support cancelling and at any point
支持取消，并在任何时候
right so canceled based on the canceled
权利因此被取消，基于已取消
event cancel all right and we're gonna
活动取消好了，我们要
duplicate that again here for the the
在这里再次复制
paid you know if it's in the page date
支付给您，知道它是否在页面日期中
when I'm able to cancel it as well so
当我也可以取消它时
here
这里
paid to cancel based on the canceled
支付基于取消的取消
event and then finally I wanna cancel it
事件，最后我想取消它
if it's in the fulfilled state right so
如果它处于完成状态，那么
with external that source fulfilled that
与外部的来源实现了
target will be cancelled and then event
目标将被取消，然后发生事件
will be canceled all right there we are
将会被取消，我们在那里
so there's our numerous different states
所以有很多不同的状态
here right it's going from a you know
在这里，这是从你知道的
submitted to paid paid to fulfilled and
提交到已付
filled of course is our final one right
当然，这是我们的最后一项权利
so that's that's our successfully
这就是我们的成功
finished workflow or state machine we
完成工作流程或状态机
also have submitted to canceled we have
也已经提交取消我们有
paid to cancelled and fulfilled to
支付给取消并履行
cancel then one one could argue that
取消，然后有人可能会说
this isn't very useful so maybe we'll
这不是很有用，所以也许我们会
actually get rid of that one right it
实际上摆脱了那个权利吧
doesn't
不
I don't not sure if that one it's all
我不确定那是不是全部
that much use all that useful since
这么多用所有有用的
they're both terminal states but okay so
他们都是终端国家，但是很好
there we go there's our there's our
我们去那里我们那里我们那里
states and that is our that's it right
国家，那是我们的权利
we've configured a single state machine
我们已经配置了一个状态机
you know it's a lot of configuration but
你知道这是很多配置，但是
you get a working result so that's let's
您会得到一个有效的结果，所以让我们
actually try it out let's actually use
实际尝试一下，让我们实际使用
the state machine and just you know
状态机，只有你知道
advance it right let's just use it to to
推进它，让我们使用它来
move data to move the token represented
移动数据以移动表示的令牌
but
但
state machine from one state to another
从一个状态到另一状态的状态机
so I'm going to actually create a
所以我实际上要创建一个
command line runner that creates a that
创建那个的命令行运行器
takes a manage of a state machine
管理状态机
factory so class runner implements
工厂，所以上课者实施
application runner and we'll inject our
应用程序运行程序，我们将注入
private final state machine factory
私人最终状态机工厂
order States order events factory all
订单状态订单事件工厂全部
right
对
enter that all right good look at that
输入那个好吧，看看那个
so this dot factory dot get state
所以这个点工厂点得到状态
machine this stuff factory don't get the
机器这东西工厂不明白
state machine so that's it actually with
状态机，实际上就是这样
that's the the result there we have our
那就是我们拥有的结果
state machine we have a valid a new
状态机，我们有一个有效的新
instance of the state machine we can
我们可以的状态机实例
also provide a unique ID for one you
还为您提供一个唯一的ID
like to have multiple instances so maybe
喜欢有多个实例，所以也许
you have a state machine for you know a
你有一个状态机，你知道
particular order number right order 75
特定订单号右订单75
whatever right whatever you want
随便你想要什么
whenever you want to be able to
每当你想能够
correlate or to be able to you know
相关或能够知道
correlate the the state machine to
将状态机关联到
whatever it external state you've got so
无论你处于何种外部状态
let's see what happens that's actually
让我们看看实际上发生了什么
it event let's interact with this so
它让我们与此互动
machine dot start right so let's say it
机器点开始正确，所以说出来
start and then we'll say a machine dot
开始，然后我们说一个机器点
get state and that'll give us the
取得状态，这会给我们
current state and we're gonna get the ID
当前状态，我们将获得ID
and then the name all right so let's
然后这个名字好吧，让我们
print it out it's actually a log that
打印出来实际上是一个日志
out so when it's a hat log and we'll go
出来，当它是一个帽子日志，我们会去
down here log info current state is that
这里的日志信息当前状态是
Alright run the code
好的运行代码
all right what did we get so the state
好吧，我们得到了什么，所以状态
changed we saw the listener their state
改变了，我们看到了听众的状态
changed from Noll so you know it's the
从Noll改变了，所以你知道
first one to object states submitted
第一个反对提交的州
mine up so it when it first started up
挖掘它，以便它在第一次启动时
it automatically goes to the initial
它会自动转到初始
state which is submitted we can see that
提交的状态，我们可以看到
the machine has actually started and so
机器实际上已经启动，所以
these are the different states the
这些是不同的状态
current state is submitted here's the
当前状态是这里提交的
UUID for it and there's the random you
它的UUID，并且您是随机的
know ID that we gave it we printed out
知道我们给它的ID，我们将其打印出来
the current state it said submitted
它说提交的当前状态
right and that's it they program
对，就是他们编程
finished at that point so that's let's
在这一点上完成了，让我们
keep going now let's say that wanna
现在继续前进，我们想说
trigger the the movement from fulfilled
触发运动完成
to paid so now we can send an event we
支付，所以现在我们可以发送事件我们
can do it a couple different ways we can
可以通过几种不同的方式做到这一点
say order events and then just pass in
说订单事件，然后传递
one of the events order events dot
事件顺序事件点之一
fulfill that'll that'll give us more so
实现那会给我们更多
now to put that down there again and
现在再把它放在那里
we'll run this application all right so
我们将运行该应用程序，这样
if we look at this current state again
如果我们再看看这个当前状态
submitted Oh what did I do wrong we said
提交哦，我做错了什么，我们说
oh it's submitted we have to pay don'twe
哦，它已经提交了，我们必须付钱
see I can't that's a good actually
看到我不能，那实际上是一件好事
that's a good demo I can't go from
那是一个很好的演示，我不能从
submitted to fulfilled I have to go
提交实现我必须去
through the predictable well-known
通过可预知的知名度
states here right it's not gonna let me
声明这里正确，它不会让我
enter an invalid state so I'm not gonna
进入无效状态，所以我不会
be able to do something that's outside
能够做外面的事情
of the the design of the state machine
状态机的设计
which is exactly what we want right want
这正是我们想要的权利
a predictable deterministic progression
可预测的确定性进展
we want to know that it's not possible
我们想知道这是不可能的
to accidentally arrive at a you know too
偶然到达一个你也知道
far ahead in the processing without all
在处理过程中遥遥领先
the preconditions which is to say all
前提是所有
the previous states having been
以前的状态是
satisfied so there we are current state
满意，所以我们处于当前状态
equals paid right so we know we got that
等于有偿权利，所以我们知道我们得到了
that's the second time where the current
这是第二次
the first state was submitted and then
提交了第一个状态，然后
it says paid now that's that's send the
它说现在付款，这就是发送
another event send event and this time
另一个事件发送事件，这次
instead of using the you know object
而不是使用您知道的对象
itself will send a message using the
本身将使用
Spring Framework message builder Spring
Spring Framework 消息生成器Spring
Framework you know the Spring Framework
您知道Spring Framework
messaging message builder this is the
消息传递消息生成器，这是
same message builder that you use for
您用于的同一消息生成器
bring integration that's the same one
带来相同的整合
used for the WebSocket support and
用于WebSocket支持和
spring MVC it's you know it's the simp
Spring MVC是您知道的
the JMS messaging template and the JMS
JMS消息传递模板和JMS
and the mqp messaging template and all
以及mqp消息传递模板以及所有
that stuff all used the same basic thing
这些东西都使用相同的基本东西
here so I'm gonna say with payload and
在这里，我要说有效载荷和
what are we gonna say and the payload is
我们要说什么，有效载荷是
gonna be of course an event order events
当然会成为一个事件命令事件
dot want to fulfill right whoops
点想要实现正确的呼声
fulfill I'm going to build that and the
满足我要去建立那个
reason this is important is because you
之所以如此重要，是因为您
can actually craft reason that we have
实际上可以制造出我们拥有的理由
the second variant is because you can
第二个变体是因为您可以
craft a message that has headers right I
制作具有正确标题的邮件
can say set header a equals B right for
可以说将标头设置为a等于B
example and as we can see in a bezel see
例子，就像我们在边框中看到的那样
in a bit those headers can be useful in
这些标题可能会在
your code need a component logic so
您的代码需要组件逻辑，因此
let's move that down here and then run
让我们将其移至此处然后运行
the application and let's see let go
该应用程序，让我们看看放手
awesome okay so we can see the current
很棒，所以我们可以看到最新的
state is now fulfilled all right so
现在状态已经实现了，所以
we've gotten the fulfilled support that
我们得到了充实的支持，
we've got we've got submitted paid and
我们已经提交了报酬，
fulfilled that's working as expected we
实现了预期的工作，我们
can interact with the state machine at
可以与状态机进行交互
any time
任何时候
and we get a sort of a well-known thing
我们得到了一种众所周知的东西
a well known quantity all right that's
众所周知的数量
that's a all very well and good of
一切都很好
course but it is at the end of the day
当然，但是到了最后
just you know it's just we're just
只是你知道这就是我们
moving state around in memory we're not
在内存中移动状态，我们不是
doing anything based on it and right
根据它做正确的事
we're not actually acting on it so you
我们实际上并没有对此采取行动，所以您
have a couple of places where you could
有几个地方可以
do that first of all you can actually
首先要做到这一点
provide state entry handlers all right
提供状态输入处理程序
so you can say based on the you could
所以你可以说基于
say based on whenever somebody orders
根据某人的命令说
enters the submitted state you have a
输入您拥有的提交状态
handler so a new action looks like that
处理程序，所以一个新动作看起来像那样
right so your job is to to do something
对，所以你的工作是做某事
that reflects that were in the state
反映出当时的状态
maybe you want to write a record to the
也许你想写一条记录到
database maybe you want to send a
数据库，也许你想发送一个
notification or put a send a message on
通知或发送消息
a cue or whatever you want right so
提示或您想要的任何东西
entering submitted
输入已提交
right and you could have new data but
对，您可能会有新数据，但是
you can actually have data that is
您实际上可以拥有的数据是
encoded in this order so it might you
以此顺序编码，因此您可能会
might have a data that comes from the
可能有来自
message that we talked about earlier you
我们之前谈到的消息
could actually pulled it out here so if
实际上可以将其拉出此处，如果
you wanted to so the context get events
您想让上下文获得事件
right this is the event get extended
对，这是活动得到扩展
state you can get variables all right so
声明您可以正确获取变量，因此
I can get order ID if I want to get or
如果我想获取或可以获取订单ID
default so let's say it's negative one
默认值，所以说它是负数
long order ID so I'm I'm now class dot
长单号，所以我现在是班级点
cast there we are so this is me
我们在那里，所以这就是我
extracting out either a negative one or
提取负数或
an order ID from the extended state in
来自扩展状态的订单ID
the and state machine so let's actually
和状态机，所以让我们实际
let's see if we can send that into the
让我们看看是否可以将其发送到
state machine before we start it up
启动之前的状态机
right so here we go entering state
对，所以我们进入状态
machine order ID is and it will write
机器订单ID是，它将写入
out the order ID okay so now we have to
退出订单ID好，现在我们必须
actually send this order ID that's a
实际发送的订单ID是
precondition for this to work right it's
使其正常工作的前提是
going to fail it's gonna blow chunks
失败了，它会炸成碎片
spectacularly if we don't have that
如果我们没有那个
order ID so let's go back to our state
订单ID，让我们回到我们的状态
machine here before we kick it off get
我们开始之前的机器
extended state get variables put if
扩展状态获取变量，如果
absent order ID and we'll actually say
缺少订单ID，我们实际上会说
I'll actually extract that out into a
我实际上将其提取到
separate value later so we'll say long
稍后再分开值，所以我们会说长
order ID equals this and we'll put this
订单ID等于此，我们将其放入
in here we'll say long that to string
在这里，我们会说长串
order ID
订单编号
I'll put order ID in there so we're
我将订单ID放在那里
putting that in there before we launch
在我们启动之前把它放在那里
the process before we launch the the
我们启动
state machine let's now run this again
状态机现在让我们再次运行它
and see what we get
看看我们得到了什么
all right so if we go here
好吧，如果我们去这里
okay order ID is 1 3 2 3 2 just as we
好的订单ID是1 3 2 3 2
expect right and drink submitted state
期待正确并喝酒提交状态
so here we have the ability to propagate
所以在这里我们有能力传播
you know to to perpetuate state from one
你知道要从一个国家延续下去
node to another in the graph and the
图中的另一个节点和
state machine this is very convenient
状态机这很方便
you can do all sorts of hand or logic
你可以做各种各样的手或逻辑
there and that handle logic it can be
在那里，它可以处理逻辑
here or you could just call another
在这里或者你可以打电话给另一个
function you can call another thing
您可以调用其他功能的功能
right so you could actually use spring
对，所以您实际上可以使用spring
integration here you could use spring
集成在这里你可以使用spring
batch you can do whatever you want to
批处理您可以做任何您想做的事
but you can maintain sort of this a
但您可以维持这种
well-known progression of State spring
国家春季的著名进展
state machine is useful by the way for
状态机是有用的
all the like I said it's particularly
就像我说的那样
useful I think in these long lived sort
我认为在这些长期存在的情况下很有用
of distributed transactions or
分布式交易或
distributed worker in you know scenarios
您所知道的场景中的分布式工作人员
we have lots of moving parts that have
我们有很多运动部件
to coordinate their state ok so this is
协调他们的状态好，所以这是
how you would provide your own custom
您将如何提供自己的风俗习惯
behavior right ok so that's that's
正确的行为，那就是
that's convenient
那很方便
I want you know we've looked now also by
我想你知道我们现在也看过
the way at how to launch an instance of
如何启动实例的方式
the state machine and to how to activate
状态机以及如何激活
it let's go ahead and comment this out
让我们继续进行评论
now and that let's actually wrap a
现在，让我们实际包装一个
service around this machine a service
围绕这台机器的服务
set manages our entity for us and does
集为我们管理我们的实体并做到
things you know it's got some semblance
你知道的东西看起来很像
of business logic written so I'm going
编写了业务逻辑，所以我要去
to create a order service class would be
创建订单服务类将是
an order service class order service and
订单服务类订单服务，以及
we'll use JPA here to describe an order
我们将在这里使用JPA来描述订单
so class order at entity and it's going
所以在实体上的课程顺序
to have a private long ID private what
有一个私人的长ID私人什么
else do we need I guess a lot I guess
否则我们需要我猜很多吗
the ID is actually all we really need
该ID实际上就是我们真正需要的
isn't it so date we could say date time
是不是这样，日期我们可以说是日期时间
you know whenever the job was when they
你知道每当工作是什么时候
were whenever the order was made so
是什么时候下订单
that's the essence there we need the ID
这就是我们需要ID的本质
and at generate value alright so we want
在产生价值的过程中，所以我们想要
that but of course in order for this to
那当然是为了
be useful when you get her some setters
当你得到她一些二传手时会很有用
so we'll use Lombok again all args
所以我们将再次使用Lombok的所有参数
constructor at data
数据构造函数
get the gun you know the getters and
得到你知道吸气剂的枪，
setters all this stuff so this is GPA
设置所有这些东西，所以这就是GPA
these 3a Lombok right
这些3a龙目岛对
okay let's see okay so we have that way
好吧，让我们看看好吧，我们有那样的方法
I guess we need a repository now so
我想我们现在需要一个存储库，所以
let's go ahead and build a repository
让我们继续构建一个存储库
interface order repository extends jpay
接口订单存储库扩展了jpay
repository managing entities is hyper
存储库管理实体是超级
order whose partner case I'll type it
我要输入其伴侣案的订单
long and we won't actually use that in
很长时间，我们实际上不会在
our service so in our service we're
我们的服务，所以在我们的服务中
going to inject the repository private
将注入存储库为私有
final order repository and our service
最终订单存储库和我们的服务
is going to have a few different methods
将有几种不同的方法
write a few of them mark I think fairly
写一些，我觉得还不错
obvious let's look at the first one
显而易见，让我们看一下第一个
which is order we're gonna actually
这是我们实际上要执行的命令
create a order when somebody gives us a
当有人给我们一个订单时创建一个订单
date and I guess that's the only thing
日期，我想那是唯一的事情
we need for our date time after all so
我们毕竟需要约会时间
we're gonna say public order actually it
我们要说的是公共秩序
can just be order it doesn't really
可以命令它不是真的
matter does it when I have a new method
当我有一个新方法时，事关重大
here order
在这里订购
so given a you know we could call this
所以给定一个，你知道我们可以称之为
crate or something I guess there we go
板条箱或其他我想可以去的东西
and I will say when somebody gives us a
我会说有人给我们一个
date we're going to create an order so
我们要创建订单的日期
we can say we turn this that order
我们可以说我们把这个命令
repository dot save new order and the
存储库点保存新订单，并且
first parameter is the ID which we don't
第一个参数是我们不使用的ID
need we also should have the actual the
需要我们还应该有实际的
actual state shouldn't wait why not
实际状态不应该等待，为什么不
order is gonna progress from one state
秩序将从一个国家进步
to another so we want to manage that so
到另一个，所以我们要设法做到这一点
let's actually look at let's talk about
让我们来看看
how we can persist that state we want
我们如何保持我们想要的状态
that we want this order to to go to a
我们希望此订单转到
well-known state and those can
众所周知的州，那些可以
correspond to the the states and the
对应于州和
state machine so we're gonna store it as
状态机，所以我们将其存储为
a string but we're gonna actually create
一个字符串，但我们实际上要创建
a constructor I'm going to create
我要创建的构造函数
constructor that can take our enum
可以使用我们的枚举的构造函数
values so I'm gonna say date D and then
值，所以我要说日期D然后
the order States OS so this dot date
订单状态OS，因此该日期
time equals D this dot state equals OS
时间等于D此点状态等于OS
name that okay so this is the string
可以的名字，所以这是字符串
representation of the enum this is a
枚举的表示形式，这是一个
Java isn't right all in ohms have the
Java是不对的
ability to produce a name that
产生名字的能力
corresponds to the basically to the to
基本上对应于
the symbol that you see in the unit cell
您在单位单元格中看到的符号
until in our case it'll be um it'll be a
直到在我们的情况下，它将是一个
you know fulfilled in all that stuff
你知道所有的事情都实现了
alright so maybe I'll make that public
好吧，也许我会公开
good and the idea of course will be
好，这个主意当然会
automatic auto and commented and
自动自动和评论和
generated for us by the by their by JP
由JP为我们生成
so let's use this new version here this
所以我们在这里使用这个新版本
new constructor and the order state will
新的构造函数，订单状态将
be of course fulfilled or I started
当然会实现或我开始
submitted right and I'm cheating a
提交权，我在欺骗
little bit there I should perhaps check
那里我应该检查一下
am a state machine but let's assume we
是一个状态机，但让我们假设我们
already know we can take that for
已经知道我们可以接受
granted that all orders when they start
开始时授予所有订单
are at the order states submitted state
处于订单状态提交状态
so very good and you know we might even
非常好，你知道我们甚至
have a some getters and setters for that
有一些吸气剂和二传手
so public order state get order state
所以公共秩序状态得到秩序状态
turn this dot state I'm going to say
把这个点状状态我要说
order states that value of right and I
秩序表明权利的价值和我
get that string and use that to arrive
得到那个字符串，并使用它来到达
at the enum and we're gonna have a
在枚举中，我们将有一个
writer as well set order state taking in
编写者以及设置订单状态
the order state and writing it out so
订单状态并将其写出
this dot state equals s game saying this
这个点状态等于游戏说
before and we could even just use that
之前，我们甚至可以使用它
cetera here set an order state oh yes
此处的cetera设置了订单状态哦是
very good okay so now we need to to
很好，所以现在我们需要
manage that state we need to actually
管理该状态，我们实际上需要
manage the state machine so let's
管理状态机，让我们
imagine in our runner we're actually
想象在跑步者中，我们实际上是
gonna call that that order service here
会在这里打电话给那个订购服务
so let's go to our runner where is that
所以我们去跑步吧
runner it's up here I'm gonna move our
跑步者在这里，我要移动我们的
order service a little bit closer to a
点餐服务更接近
work up here close to the runner so we
在靠近跑步者的地方工作，所以我们
can actually balance back and forth with
可以与
a bit of ease alright so there we are
有点轻松，好吧，我们在那里
the order service is just above the
订单服务就在
runner we're gonna get rid of all of
跑步者，我们将摆脱所有
this since we already understand what's
因为我们已经了解了什么
happening there and we're gonna make it
在那里发生，我们要做到
a little easier to keep everything in
让一切都变得容易一些
sight here so I'm gonna move this to the
视线在这里，所以我要把它移到
top so we can balance back and forth
顶部，这样我们就可以来回平衡
this runner will be our simple little
这个跑步者将是我们简单的小家伙
test and it we probably should just
测试，我们大概应该
write a test but let's just keep it the
写一个测试，但让我们保持它
same code page here shall we all right
相同的代码页在这里我们可以吗
so order order will be a order I'm going
所以订单将是我要去的订单
to use the order service
使用订单服务
so we'll say order service wouldn't
所以我们会说订购服务不会
reject that we don't need this anymore
拒绝我们不再需要这个
inject the order service order service
注入订单服务订单服务
add the constructor get rid of the
添加构造函数摆脱
factory that's in the order service it's
订单服务中的工厂
buried in the order service for us I'm
为我们埋葬在订单服务中
going to say this that order service dot
要说这个订单服务点
create new order service okay very good
创建新订单服务还可以
so those are our order now let's suppose
所以这些现在是我们的订单
that we want to change that order right
我们想要更改订单的权利
maybe we have different business logic
也许我们有不同的业务逻辑
events right we could actually have you
对的事情我们实际上可以请你
know somebody clicks on a button so then
知道有人点击按钮，然后
it's but we want to make sure that the
是，但是我们要确保
workflow moves to the paid state right
工作流移至已付款状态
and then somebody you know maybe they
然后你知道的人也许他们
maybe they've filled out the form and
也许他们已经填写了表格，
they've filled out the credit card
他们已经填写了信用卡
information so I want to make sure that
信息，所以我想确保
the state machine reflects that it's
状态机反映出
been paid and then finally you know a
付了钱，最后你知道了
day later a labels been printed out and
一天后，标签被打印出来，
put on a box and the order is now
放在盒子上，现在订购
fulfilled all right so we want to make
履行了所有权利，所以我们要
sure that when they click that button on
确保当他们单击该按钮时
their mobile phone in the warehouse that
他们在仓库里的手机
the order reflects that state as well so
该命令也反映了该状态
we need some way of telling them you
我们需要某种方式告诉他们你
know we're gonna have imagine a number
知道我们会想像一个数字
of different methods we're gonna go
我们将要去的不同方法
ahead and just implement one sort of
向前并实施一种
omnibus method here that moves the order
此处移动命令的综合方法
from one state to another but you can
从一个州到另一个州，但是你可以
imagine having the same basic logic you
想像一下您拥有相同的基本逻辑
know reused across different bits of
知道在不同的位置重复使用
functionality you know different you
您知道的功能与众不同
know it's a backing service that
知道这是一项支持服务
different clients will talk to so let's
不同的客户会交谈，所以让我们
go ahead and do that well okay to a
继续做下去，好吧
method here called change okay so change
这里的方法叫做change好的，所以改
is in our order service over here and
在我们的订单服务中
the change method will return the state
change方法将返回状态
machine itself alright so we want to
机器本身很好，所以我们想
actually have the state machine itself
实际上有状态机本身
but I think in order to do that we can
但我认为，为了做到这一点，我们可以
actually need to have a method that
实际需要一种方法
actually builds the state machine for a
实际上是为
given order so let's let's start with
给定顺序，让我们开始吧
the business logic thing the business
业务逻辑事物
object focus thing which is what you
对象焦点的东西，这就是你
know she care about here that's the EM
知道她在乎这就是新兴市场
that's this and when I order ID and I'm
就是这样，当我订购ID时，
gonna have an order events parameter
将有一个订单事件参数
here in order for this to work we're
在这里为了这个工作我们
gonna need to have a way of arriving at
需要有一种到达的方法
the the state machine so SM and we need
状态机，所以SM，我们需要
to arrive at the state machine so let's
到达状态机，让我们
just say this step build and we're going
只需说出这一步，我们就可以
to pass in the order ID and create that
传递订单ID并创建
is a private implementation method here
是这里的私有实现方法
because there's a lot that needs to
因为有很多需要
happen here so first things first we
发生在这里，所以第一件事首先我们
need to look up the record we need to
需要查询我们需要的记录
look up the ID here so I'll actually
在这里查找ID，以便我实际
first let's return that make that
首先让我们返回
compile and to do there's some stuff
编译并做一些事情
that we need to do there but first we
我们需要在那里做，但是首先我们
need to arrive we need to vend a new
需要到达，我们需要出售一个新的
instance so we're not gonna actually
实例，所以我们实际上不会
persist the state machine itself but we
坚持状态机本身，但我们
need to rehydrate a state machine we
需要给状态机补水
needs a factory a new state machine
需要工厂新的状态机
based on the order and then push it to a
根据订单，然后将其推送到
certain state right away if the order
如果命令立即进入特定状态
reflects the fact that the that it's
反映了一个事实，那就是
already been fulfilled then we want the
已经实现了，那么我们想要
corresponding state machine arms that we
我们对应的状态机武器
get back from this build method to
从这种构建方法回到
reflect that so we need to do a couple
反映这一点，所以我们需要做一些
things here first of all look up the
这里的事情首先要查找
order the existing one this dot order
订购现有的一个此点顺序
repository that find one by its order ID
通过其订单ID查找一个的存储库
and then we want to turn in turn that
然后我们要反过来
into a key so order ID t equals long dot
密钥，因此订单ID t等于长点
to string order dot get ID and then i
字符串顺序点获取ID，然后我
want a factory a new state machine so
想要工厂一个新的状态机，所以
order state's order events SM equals
订单状态的订单事件SM等于
this dot factory and we need the state
这个点工厂，我们需要状态
machine factory so this dot state
机器工厂所以这个点状态
machine factory oh and you don't have
机器工厂哦，你没有
that injected here so private final
在这里注入了私人决赛
state machine factory and it'll be order
状态机工厂，将要订购
States order events factory
国令活动工厂
all right good stuff look at that so
好东西好好看
this dot factory dot get state machine
这个点工厂点获取状态机
passing on the ID and the idea is the
传递ID，想法是
order ID key there good so that's our
那里的订单ID键很好，这就是我们的
state machine but again this state
状态机，但再次这种状态
machine hasn't been started remember how
机器还没启动还记得
we used it before we have to call start
我们在调用开始之前就用过它
we have to do all this stuff but when we
我们必须做所有这些事情，但是当我们
call start it's gonna start at submitted
呼叫开始它将在提交开始
and this order might be an order that's
这个订单可能是
you know all but fulfilled for example
你知道所有，但实现了
so we want to well I have to do a few
所以我们要好，我必须做一些
things here we need to actually tell the
这里的事情我们需要真正告诉
state machine to reset itself to our
状态机以将自己重置为我们的
particular state so let's do that here
特定状态，所以让我们在这里做
we're gonna say state machine
我们要说状态机
don't stop first of all we don't want it
首先不要停止我们不想要的
running first of all if it is already
首先运行（如果已经运行）
started and then we're gonna we're
开始，然后我们要
actually gonna say SM dot get state
其实会说SM点得到状态
machine accessor right this is guess
机器访问权，这是猜测
this gives us the ability to do some
这使我们有能力做一些
things to visit the the nodes in the
拜访节点中的事物
directed graph that is the state machine
状态机的有向图
so we can get the state machine accessor
这样我们就可以获得状态机访问器
and then we can visit all the regions
然后我们可以参观所有地区
right so again when you think about a
是的，当您想到一个
state machine you you need to understand
您需要了解的状态机
that state machines can themselves
状态机可以自己
recurse on other state machines you can
可以在其他状态机上递归
have nodes that then lead to other state
有节点然后导致其他状态
machines on you know in a hierarchical
您知道的机器是分层的
sort of fashion or and so you have these
某种时尚或，所以你有这些
these are called regions each one of
这些被称为区域
these state machines nested or not
这些状态机是否嵌套
it's called a region and I want to visit
这是一个地区，我想去参观
each region so I'm going to visit each
每个地区，所以我要去参观每个
region here so I'm going to say do with
这里的区域，所以我要说
all regions and I'm gonna provide a
所有地区，我将提供
state machine function so new state
状态机功能如此新的状态
machine and function and the state
机器，功能和状态
machine function has a very simple apply
机器功能有一个非常简单的应用
method and in there I'm given a SMA a
方法，在那里我给了SMA
state machine access so SMA I'll say
状态机访问，所以我会说SMA
state SMA dot reset state machine so
状态SMA点重置状态机，因此
that's the first thing I'm going to do
那是我要做的第一件事
is I'm going to make sure that we have a
我要确保我们有一个
new default state machine context that
新的默认状态机上下文
takes as its first parameter here the
此处将其作为第一个参数
state that I want our object to be in so
声明我希望我们的物体处于
I'm gonna I'm gonna extract I'm gonna
我要去提取我要去
look at the current state of the object
看物体的当前状态
which is order dot get order state
订单点获取订单状态
and then use that here okay so I'm
然后在这里使用它，所以我
resetting I'm telling the state machine
重置我告诉状态机
that even though you are submitted right
即使你被正确提交
now I'm moving you forcibly to whatever
现在我要把你强行带到任何地方
state you're supposed to be in so that
声明你应该在
we can have a you know a predictable
我们可以让您知道可预测的
progression from here and then
从这里开始然后
everything else everything else can be
其他一切都可以
known right sonal for now no and no all
现在知道正确的声纳
right and of course this can be a lambda
对，当然这可以是lambda
which is a nice thing to have well come
来是一件好事
wait we might actually need this again
等等，我们可能真的需要这个
later so let's leave that as is but we
稍后，让我们保持现状，但是我们
can certainly get you can use the
当然可以让你可以使用
diamond syntax there from Java 7 alright
Java 7中的钻石语法
so we we've got that now and that I
所以我们现在已经有了
think should do it so let's actually
认为应该这样做，所以让我们实际上
start up the state machine for now start
启动状态机以立即启动
it up and return it now of course the
它并返回现在当然
question that comes up is you know how
出现的问题是你知道如何
are we going to persist this record how
我们要坚持这个记录如何
is this repository ever gonna find that
这个储存库会发现
record in the first place something
首先记录一些东西
needs to take care to persist this state
需要注意保持这种状态
changes with the entity itself right so
随着实体本身的变化而改变
when entity when they when the statement
当实体当他们当陈述
state machine changes I want to update
我要更新的状态机更改
that state field on the Jaypee entity so
Jaypee实体上的那个state字段，所以
here we need to add a state machine
在这里我们需要添加一个状态机
interceptor here so we'll say SMA dot
这里是拦截器，所以我们说SMA点
and state machine interceptor new state
和状态机拦截器的新状态
machine interceptor and this gives me I
机器拦截器，这给了我
maybe I should use the adapter will use
也许我应该使用适配器将使用
the adapter here because there's a
这里的适配器，因为有一个
number of different callback methods and
各种不同的回调方法和
it's order states and order events
这是订单状态和订单事件
alright and get rid of that
好吧，摆脱掉
goody all right so we need to write
好吧，好吧，我们需要写
write the state into the database before
在将状态写入数据库之前
every single state change or we could do
每个状态的改变，或者我们可以做
it after I guess it really doesn't
我猜它真的没有
matter but for our purposes I want to
很重要，但出于我们的目的，我想
write it down in the database and you
把它写在数据库里，你
know there's no reason that this method
知道没有理由使用这种方法
couldn't take place in the same resource
不能在同一资源中发生
local transaction if you're persisting
如果您坚持要进行本地交易
the you know this is a state change
你知道这是一个状态变化
that's gonna happen in our JP entity
这将发生在我们的JP实体中
there's no reason that the state change
没有理由改变状态
couldn't happen in the same context in
不可能在同一背景下发生
the same thread as your business logic
与您的业务逻辑相同的线程
changes as well but in this case it
也会发生变化，但在这种情况下
doesn't you know you could also do it
你不知道你也可以做到吗
you can also persist this completely
您也可以完全坚持
separately from your entity right
与您的实体权利分开
okay so P state change what we're gonna
好的，所以P状态改变了我们要做什么
do is going to say that we're expecting
要做的是说我们在期待
a parameter to you know a header to come
您知道的参数头
in on the event that trigger the state
在触发状态的事件中
change all right this is why we showed
改变一切，这就是为什么我们表现出
you that message builder variant or
您是消息生成器的变体，还是
you're on the variant of sending an
您正在发送一个变体
event into the state machine you can
事件可以进入状态机
send either the enum value or we can
发送枚举值或我们可以
send a spring framework messaging
发送一个Spring Framework 消息
message with a header and that header
带有标题和该标题的消息
option is let's assume that that's what
选项是，假设这就是
we're going to use because that hasn't
我们将要使用，因为那还没有
the ability to convey parameters headers
传达参数标题的能力
right values that we can pass into the
正确的价值观，我们可以传递给
state machine which we can use in this
我们可以在其中使用的状态机
case to to persist our our data so we're
保留我们的数据的情况，所以我们
gonna say that if the message that we
要说如果我们
are given here is not null all right so
在这里给出不是null吧，所以
I'm gonna say if it's present then we
我要说如果它存在，那么我们
want to do something with it and what
想用它做些什么
I'm gonna do well we want to want to get
我要做好，我们想得到
out the ID so the order ID is the value
删除ID，以便订单ID为值
that we're gonna get from the message
我们将从消息中得到
get headers dot get or default and it's
获取标题点获取或默认值，它是
gonna be called order ID negative one so
将被称为订单ID负数
we actually looked at this exact same
我们实际上看着这个完全一样
thing earlier on and we're gonna say
更早的事情，我们要说
that optional dot of knowable
已知的可选点
right if and if that's knowable then
是的，如果那是已知的，那么
rather if it's present order ID then we
而是如果它是当前的订单ID，那么我们
wanted to process it so we have the ID
想处理它，所以我们有ID
and if it's present we're gonna get the
如果存在，我们将得到
order order equals order repository dot
订单订单等于订单库点
find one and we'll put the order ID in
找到一个，我们将订单ID放入
get it out of the database we're gonna
从数据库中获取它
update the state so I'm gonna say order
更新状态，所以我要说命令
dot set state and the state will be
点设置状态，状态将为
whatever state we're progressing to in
无论我们进展到什么状态
that state of course is passed into this
那状态当然会传递给
callback here so state get ID dot name
在这里回调，以便获得ID点名称
write that out tonight or we can
今晚写出来，否则我们可以
actually just a set or state I suppose
我想实际上只是一个集合或状态
that would have been easier so said or
这样说会容易些，或者
stayed there we go dot get ID all right
呆在那里，我们去点ID就好了
it's there's that and we want to say
就在那里，我们想说
order repository dot safe so order very
订购资料库点安全，因此非常订购
good okay so that's a what's happening
很好，那就是发生了什么事
here we've got a callback when the state
这里我们有一个回调，当状态
machines enters a particular stage we
机器进入特定阶段
want to write before it enters we want
想在它进入之前写
to write down the state that it's going
写下即将发生的状态
to arrive at and you know we want to do
到达，你知道我们想做
that we want to tie that to the order
我们想要将其与订单联系起来
itself and we need to do that by linking
本身，我们需要通过链接来做到这一点
our linking our change we you know to a
我们将我们的变化与我们联系起来
parameter that tells us which order is
告诉我们哪个顺序的参数
affected here right so let's revisit our
在这里受到影响，所以让我们重新来看一下
code here clean that up a little bit all
这里的代码清理一点点所有
right
对
good so that's a bit cleaner I like that
好，这样有点干净我喜欢
and I'm all about clean code so we've
而且我都是关于干净代码的，所以我们已经
got now our state machine we've got a
现在有我们的状态机
state machine accessor all of this is
状态机访问器，所有这一切是
being configured on every brand new
在每一个全新的配置
state machine right so again the state
状态机正确，所以再次状态
machine is a very lightweight object but
机器是很轻的物体，但是
we're going to do some very heavyweight
我们将做一些非常重量级的
things are going to talk to a database
事情将要与数据库对话
and persistent state very very easily
和持久状态非常非常容易
though Ryan doesn't take a lot to make
尽管Ryan不需要花很多钱
this to tie the state machines advances
这与国家机器的发展息息相关
to state and our business logic so we're
陈述和我们的业务逻辑，所以我们
gonna get the best of both worlds we get
会得到两全其美的
our business logic which is clean we get
我们的业务逻辑是干净的
a definitive you know state machine and
你知道状态机的权威
a model of how these things are supposed
这些事物的模型
to progress and so on so okay good now
进步等等，现在还好吧
let's see what happens if we if we run
让我们看看如果我们跑步
this what happens right so we want to be
这是正确的事情，所以我们想成为
able to this will actually create a
能够做到这一点实际上会创建一个
state machine that'll build a state
建立状态的状态机
machine here we want to build to change
我们要建造的机器来改变
the the flow the state of the myth of
神话的状态
the state machine so maybe we could do
状态机，所以也许我们可以做
this maybe we actually say hey you know
这也许我们实际上是说嘿
and then here we could say we can have
然后在这里我们可以说我们可以拥有
you know some property of how much was
你知道多少钱的一些性质
paid you know I'm string I don't know
付钱给你，我知道我不知道
payment confirmation number right and
付款确认号权利和
then we could actually send a message so
那么我们实际上可以发送一条消息
we could say message builder thought
我们可以说消息生成器的思想
with payload and the payload of course
有有效载荷，当然还有有效载荷
in this case is the pay event alright so
在这种情况下，付款事件还可以吗
order order
订单订单
events dot a and the header that we need
事件点a和我们需要的标题
of course the one that we must have is
当然，我们必须拥有的是
the order ID so there's the order ID and
订单ID，所以有订单ID和
we're gonna build that message like so
我们将像这样构建该消息
but we could also have you know things
但是我们也可以让你知道
like the payment confirmation number
如付款确认号
right set header payment confirmation
正确设置抬头付款确认
number or you know the price I don't
数字或你知道我不知道的价格
know whatever it doesn't really what I
知道什么不是我真正的
can actually use this in this example
可以在本例中实际使用
but it's it's the nice to know that we
但是很高兴知道我们
could send that into the the state
可以把它送进州
machine and they and then it could do as
机器，然后他们可以做为
we've seen before anything it want to
我们已经看到了它想要的任何东西
that so I'm gonna say machine or SM dot
那我要说机器或SM点
send event events message so pay message
发送事件事件消息，所以付费消息
payment message all right so that's the
付款信息没问题，那就是
first thing and we know it's gonna be
第一件事，我们知道这将是
called order ID so we can this is
叫做订单ID，所以我们可以这样
actually ideally something that you kept
理想情况下，您保留的东西
into a you've extracted into a single
到您已经提取到单个
field so you have order ID header right
字段，以便您拥有订单ID标头
the should you should have that as a
你应该把那个作为
constant somewhere and then we use that
在某个地方不变，然后我们用它
in the class so private the static final
在班级中如此私人的静态决赛
there we go order ID header there and
我们去那里的订单ID标题
you can actually have the same thing
你实际上可以拥有相同的东西
here these are well known types of
这些是众所周知的
headers good okay so that's the payment
标头很好，所以这就是付款
method what else do we want to want to
方法我们还想要什么
and this should go up good we want to
这应该很好，我们想要
have a another method that fulfills it
有另一种方法可以实现它
right so let's say we have the same
对，所以说我们有相同的
basic signature fulfill I'm gonna call
我要打电话给基本签名
this fulfill and maybe the maybe now the
这个满足，也许现在
the fulfill method takes the the address
满足方法获取地址
of where you're gonna you know the
你要去的地方
parcel you know where the the address
包裹你知道地址在哪里
whatever that you're gonna send it to I
不管你要寄给我什么
don't know it it could take anything you
不知道这可能会花费你什么
know it could be the what do you want
知道这可能是你想要的
right what do you want what are your
对，你想要什么？
whatever other information want to
任何其他信息想要
contribute to the to the object graph
有助于对象图
here but for all purposes let's just
在这里，但出于所有目的，我们只是
have a fulfill method and same basic
有一个实现方法，并且基本相同
structure right I'm going to build our
结构正确，我要建立我们的
state machine and we're then going to
状态机，然后我们将
move it to a particular state by sending
通过发送将其移至特定状态
up an event to it right so let's do that
安排一个合适的活动，让我们这样做
alright and in this case we don't have
好吧，在这种情况下，我们没有
the came confirmation so we'll say s m
来了确认，所以我们会说短信
dot send event payment message and this
点发送事件付款消息和这个
will be a fulfillment message alright
将会是一个满足的消息
then we turn sm good so there's our
然后我们把sm变好，所以我们有
fulfillment method as well payment and
履行方式以及付款方式
then fulfillment here again keep in mind
然后在这里再次实现
when we start when we start up the state
当我们开始时当我们开始时
machine we want it to get its state
我们希望它获得状态的机器
based on the state of the order all
基于订单状态
right so what's gonna happen here is
对，所以这里要发生的是
we're going to we're going to tribute
我们要致敬
the change that's going to create a
改变将创造一个
state new state machine here the state
在这里状态新的状态机
machine itself is going to look up the
机器本身将要查找
record for the object in the database
在数据库中记录对象
it's going to unpack the event the the
它会打开事件的包装
message state the order state it's gonna
消息状态订单状态
make sure that by the time we reach this
确保在我们达到目标时
line that this state machine is already
行，该状态机已经
in that state right so if it's in state
在那个状态下，所以如果它处于状态
fulfilled the third one then you know
完成了第三个，那么你知道
the state machine will reflect that
状态机将反映出
before we get to the second line now
现在我们到第二行
obviously in the second line we don't
显然，在第二行中
let's say it's in state paid or ever you
假设它处于已付款状态或您曾经
know it's just submitted so it'll be in
知道它刚刚提交，所以它会在
whatever state is supposed to be in by
任何状态应该由
the time it exits the dist up build
它离开dist up构建的时间
method and then finally we're gonna move
方法，最后我们要移动
it to the next state by sending a
通过发送一个
message into it and that is going to
消息进入其中，这将
trigger this pre state change thing
触发此状态更改前的事情
which is going to update the persistent
这将更新持久性
state in the date in the database so all
状态在数据库中的日期，所以所有
of that happens very very quickly you
你很快就会发生
know we've got actually we've now you
知道我们实际上已经有了你
know with this we're reading the data
知道这一点，我们正在读取数据
from the order object we're reading the
从订单对象中，我们正在阅读
state from the or the persistent order
从或持久顺序中得出状态
object and setting our machine to that
对象并将我们的机器设置为
and with this we're setting the changes
并以此设置更改
or synchronizing the changes to the
或将更改同步到
state machine to the order itself so
状态机对命令本身如此
bi-directional persistence alright so
双向持久性好吧
we've got our order service let's use
我们有我们的订购服务，让我们使用
this in our runner here where is our
这在我们的跑步者这里
runner hey we good here we go so order
跑步者，嘿，我们很好，我们去了，所以订单
and then in the order we're going to
然后按照顺序
we're going to send a few messages I
我们将发送一些消息
guess so we'll use the order service
猜猜吧，我们将使用订购服务
we're gonna say we've created a new one
我们要说我们已经创建了一个新的
to fulfill it now so order doctor get ID
立即履行，以便订购医生获得ID
all right no we want to pay for it first
好吧不，我们要先付钱
right so pay and we'll have the whatever
对，所以付出，我们将拥有一切
I don't know UUID don't random Doug to
我不知道UUID不会随机Doug来
strengthen okay so there's our two
加强好吧，所以我们有两个
string now if we wanted to we can we can
现在，如果我们愿意，我们可以
actually look at the state machine for
实际上看一下状态机
this that's why we returned it so
这就是为什么我们退回它的原因
payment state machine and we'll say a
付款状态机，我们会说一个
payments off state machine get event get
关闭状态机付款事件获取
state rather dot get ID dot name logged
状态而不是点获取ID点名称已记录
it out after calling pay okay
打电话后付款就可以了
goody so there's that and we're gonna
好，就是这样，我们要
have another one here called fulfilled
这里有另一个叫做实现
I'm gonna say fulfill and we know that's
我要说实现，我们知道
not going to eat that second parameter
不想吃第二个参数
so we'll use that after calling fulfill
所以我们会在调用完成后使用
and I suppose we should actually even
我想我们实际上应该
have this appear as well after calling
打电话后也有这个出现
create let's poke at the state right
让我们在状态权上戳一下
after it's been created so in this case
在创建之后，在这种情况下，
we don't actually have it so maybe we
我们实际上没有它，所以也许我们
should have returned it there right we
应该把它还给我们
could have actually had the state
本来可以有状态
machine being returned there but for now
机器返回那里，但现在
it's fine let's just think like that
很好，让我们这样想
okay so after calling fulfill we can
好吧，所以在打电话给我们后，我们可以
look at the current state as well all
看看所有的当前状态
right
对
fulfilled
完成
fulfilled state machine all right go
完成状态机可以了
so what did we do wrong
所以我们做错了什么
insert into order a hop simple newbie
插入一跳简单的新手
error order is a reserved keyword and
错误顺序是保留关键字，
sequel and I should have known that so
续集，我应该知道
let's just change the JPA entity where
让我们改变一下JPA实体
is our GP entity hands down here all
是我们的GP实体在这里所有
right
对
name equals orders sure good try again
名称等于订单，确定好，再试一次
all right let's see what we had
好吧，让我们看看我们拥有什么
so starting the state machine started
所以启动状态机就开始了
the one that had these four states state
具有这四个州的州
changed from submitted to submitted
从已提交更改为已提交
right yeah to paid good just confuse it
是的，要付高就可以了
maybe it Caesars looked down here so
也许凯撒在这里低头看
after Kong pay it's paid right that's
付完金后，那是有偿的权利
the current state after calling fulfill
调用完成后的当前状态
did I send the wrong event there in the
我在那发送了错误的事件吗
fill method right now in the logs it
现在在日志中填写方法
said oh yeah fulfil so in the fulfill
说哦，是的，所以实现
thing we have to send the right event
我们必须发送正确的事件的东西
obviously that's not gonna work on the
显然，这不会在
way so it'll it'll just stay on the old
这样，它会保留在旧的
state in the pay state so or in the paid
声明为已付款或已付款
state okay
状态还好
so after we called fulfill the result
所以在我们打电话完成结果之后
was that it was fulfilled after we
是我们完成之后
called pay the result is that the state
所谓付出的结果是国家
machine says it's paid and if you you
机器说已付款，如果您
know we can actually confirm this by
知道我们可以通过以下方式确认这一点
looking at the object and each step as
看着物体和每一步
well looking at the order itself so
好看看订单本身
let's do that where's my render okay
让我们在哪里渲染好
we're going to look up the record as
我们将查找记录为
well so this time I guess we could have
好吧，这次我想我们可以
a method that just returns the order
只返回订单的方法
itself so let's just go to the order
本身，所以让我们去订购
service here and look at the order order
服务在这里，看看订单
by ID long idea right so this thought
通过ID长的想法吧，所以这个想法
fine by ID and we'll print that out okay
按ID罚款，我们会打印出来的
so the last two methods return the state
所以最后两个方法返回状态
machine but not the order but we just
机器，但不是订单，但我们只是
want to poke at it when we just want to
当我们只想戳它时
see what's happening just to prove I
看看发生了什么，只是为了证明我
think it's working as we expect so here
认为它按预期工作，所以在这里
we'll actually say logging info order
我们实际上会说记录信息顺序
will be equal to order service dot by ID
通过ID等于订购服务点
passing in the order get ID now this
现在传递订单获取ID
line of course we can duplicate down
当然，我们可以复制下来
here as well run the code again what did
在这里再次运行代码做了什么
we get huh so order is equal to fulfill
我们得到了，所以秩序等于履行
the state is equal to fulfilled there
状态等于在那里实现
and the state is equal to paid there so
国家等于在那里支付
you can see it's synchronizing the
您可以看到它正在同步
changes back and forth alright so we've
来回改变，所以我们已经
just looked at just a very brief intro
只是看了一个非常简短的介绍
to spring state machine there's a whole
Spring Statemachine有一个整体
lot of possibilities here right now
现在有很多可能性
there's a new protocol spring cloud
有一个新的协议 Spring Cloud
skipper which I hope to also cover in a
船长，我希望也能涵盖
another installment of spring tips Ben
本期Spring 技巧的另一部分
cloud skipper that way of deploying and
云船长那种部署和
managing the lifecycle the the state
管理生命周期状态
transitions of complex applications
复杂应用的过渡
right into a cloud environment like
进入像这样的云环境
cloud foundry or kubernetes and it has a
云铸造厂或kubernetes，它有一个
need for a directed graph there's a
需要有向图，有一个
state where you deploy the app it goes
说明您在哪里部署应用程序
well or we have to roll it back or and
好，否则我们必须将其回滚或
that kind of stuff is currently right
这种东西目前是正确的
now hard-coded but we think it'd be an
现在进行了硬编码，但我们认为这将是
ideal fit for something like spring
非常适合春季之类的东西
state machine maybe that'll happen we
状态机可能会发生，我们
don't know there's you
不知道有你
for spring state machine anywhere you
适用于任何地方的Spring Statemachine
want to be able to describe the graph
希望能够描述图
separately so I I've written a fair
分别，所以我写了一个公平的
amount of code here but at the top level
此处的代码数量，但在顶层
what we care about is the fact that
我们关心的是，
these well-known transitions and their
这些众所周知的过渡及其
predictable you can interrogate it you
可预见的你可以讯问你
can print it out you can you know store
可以打印出来，你可以知道商店
it you can do all these things with that
你可以用它做所有这些事情
and you have a common way of of talking
你有一种普通的交谈方式
about this state transitions right this
关于这个状态的转变
is and this aligns your code with what
是的，这使您的代码与
the business is trying to do right
企业正试图做正确的事
alright so with that my friends thanks
好的，所以我的朋友们谢谢
so much for watching and we'll see you
这么多的观看，我们会见到你
next time
下次
you
您